<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[pump.io blog - 'releases' category]]></title><description><![CDATA[pump.io blog - 'releases' category]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/category/releases</link><generator>stratic-indexes-to-rss</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 23:17:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://pump.io/blog/category/releases/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright><![CDATA[© Copyright 2016-2017 pump.io contributors.]]></copyright><webMaster><![CDATA[AJ Jordan <alex@strugee.net>]]></webMaster><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io 5.1.4 and 5.0.4 security releases are now available]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Another day, another <a href="https://github.com/cure53/DOMPurify">DOMPurify</a> security release.</p>
<p>DOMPurify - which pump.io uses to protect against cross-site scripting vulnerabilities - today released version 2.0.16, which per the <a href="https://github.com/cure53/DOMPurify/releases/tag/2.0.16">release notes</a> fixes "an mXSS-based bypass caused by nested forms inside MathML" in Chrome. So as we usually do, the pump.io project is publishing a release that makes 2.0.16 the minimum required DOMPurify version, to make sure everyone running pump.io gets this patch.</p>
<p>Per our <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Security">security support policy</a>, we're making patches available for both the current and previous stable releases:</p>
<ol>
<li>pump.io 5.1.3 has been updated to pump.io 5.1.4</li>
<li>pump.io 5.0.3 has been updated to pump.io 5.0.4</li>
</ol>
<p>All administrators should upgrade as soon as possible since these are security releases. The risk that something will break from the upgrade is extremely low since both 5.1.4 and 5.0.3 are drop-in replacements for their predecessors. If you installed pump.io 5.1 using npm - our recommended configuration - you can upgrade with:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@5
</code></pre>
<p>If you're still running pump.io 5.0, we recommend that you take this opportunity to upgrade to pump.io 5.1 by using the above command - it's a drop-in replacement, and will require no intervention on your part. However, if you want to stick with 5.0 for now, you can install a patched version with:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@5.0
</code></pre>
<p>On the other hand, if you have a source-based install, the above commands won't work and you will need to upgrade however you usually do. This will depend on how exactly you installed pump.io in the first place.</p>
<p>If you need help, or if you have questions about these security releases, <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">the community</a> is always happy to help.</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2020/09/pump.io-5.1.4-and-5.0.4-security-releases</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2020/09/pump.io-5.1.4-and-5.0.4-security-releases</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><category><![CDATA[security]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 18:33:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io DOMPurify security fixes available]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Recently the cross-site-scripting sanitization library that pump.io uses, <a href="https://github.com/cure53/DOMPurify">DOMPurify</a>, published several security advisories for mXSS vulnerabilities affecting browsers based on the Blink rendering engine - you can find the latest one, for example, <a href="https://lists.ruhr-uni-bochum.de/pipermail/dompurify-security/2019-October/000012.html">here</a>. As we've done in the past, the pump.io project is publishing security releases to ensure that everyone is using the latest version of DOMPurify. Per our <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Security">security support policy</a>, we are providing patches for the current stable release and the previous stable release:</p>
<ol>
<li>pump.io 5.1.2 has been updated to pump.io 5.1.3</li>
<li>pump.io 5.0.2 has been updated to pump.io 5.0.3</li>
</ol>
<p>As these are security releases we encourage administrators to upgrade as soon as possible. Both 5.1.3 and 5.0.3 are drop-in replacements for their predecessors. If you have pump.io 5.1 installed via npm - our recommended configuration - you can upgrade with:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@5
</code></pre>
<p>If you're on pump.io 5.0, we recommend that you also run the above command to upgrade to 5.1 - it's a drop-in replacement for 5.0. However, if you want to stick with 5.0 for the time being, you can install a patched version with:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@5.0
</code></pre>
<p>Note that if you have a source-based install, the above commands won't work and you will need to upgrade however you usually do - this will depend on how exactly you have pump.io set up.</p>
<p>If you need help, or if you have questions about these security releases, get in touch with <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">the community</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2019/10/pump.io-dompurify-security-fixes-available</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2019/10/pump.io-dompurify-security-fixes-available</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><category><![CDATA[security]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 18:28:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io 5.1.1, Docker images, and sunsetting Node 4 support]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It's been a (relatively) long time since we've put anything on this blog, and I think it's high time for an update - especially since there are so many exciting things afoot! Not only is pump.io 5.1.1 now on npm, but we have new experimental Docker images! With <a href="https://medium.com/the-node-js-collection/april-2018-release-updates-from-the-node-js-project-71687e1f7742">upstream having already dropped security support</a>, we're also planning to drop support for Node 4 soon.</p>
<p>Let's take these one at a time.</p>
<h1>pump.io 5.1.1</h1>
<p>Several months ago I <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/pull/1438">landed</a> a patch from contributor <a href="https://github.com/vxcamiloxv">Camilo QS</a> fixing a bug in pump.io's session handling in a route serving uploads. This bug made it so that non-public uploads would always return HTTP 403 Unauthorized, even if the user actually <em>was</em> authorized. Clearly, this makes uploads unusable for people who don't like to post everything publicly. <a href="https://identi.ca/evan">Evan</a> suggested that we should backport this bugfix since it's so high-impact, and I agree. So that's what pump.io 5.1.1 contains: a bugfix for uploads. Since it's a patch release 5.1.1 is a drop-in replacement for any 5.x pump.io release, so I'd highly encourage administrators to upgrade as soon as it's convenient. We'd also love it if you <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/issues">file any bugs you find</a>, and feel free to get in touch with the <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">community</a> if you need help or have questions. As a reminder, you can subscribe to our <a href="https://lists.strugee.net/mailman/listinfo/pumpio-announce">low-volume announce mailing list</a> to get email when we put out new releases like this. Also, I would be remiss if I didn't mention that my signing key setup has changed temporarily - see <a href="https://strugee.net/blog/2018/04/new-temporary-signing-keys">here</a> if you want to cryptographically verify the 5.1.1 release.</p>
<p>If you're on an npm-based install, you can upgrade with <code>npm install -g pump.io@5.1.1</code>. If you're on a source-based install, you can upgrade by integrating the latest commits in the <code>5.1.x</code> branch. See <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#511---2018-05-05">here</a> for the changelog.</p>
<p>But that's not all. pump.io 5.1.1 also includes another exciting change: with this release, we've integrated automation to relase pump.io Docker images too.</p>
<h1>Docker images</h1>
<p>We've wanted to release pump.io Docker images for <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/issues/789">a long time</a>. But Docker has a well-known problem: security vulnerabilities in Docker Hub images <a href="https://www.infoq.com/news/2015/05/Docker-Image-Vulnerabilities">are</a> <a href="https://blog.acolyer.org/2017/04/03/a-study-of-security-vulnerabilities-on-docker-hub/">rampant</a>. Even though we've had a <code>Dockerfile</code> in the repository <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/pull/1348">for a while</a> thanks to contributor <a href="https://github.com/JanKoppe">thunfisch</a>, we didn't want to release official Docker images if we weren't sure we could always provide security support for them.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, Docker the company has done very little to address this problem. Most of their solutions are aimed at image consumers, not authors. Docker Hub has <em>some</em> capacity for automatically rebuilding images, but unfortunately, it's not enough and you end up having to roll everything yourself anwyay. Pretty disappointing - so we had to get creative.</p>
<p>Our solution to this problem is to utilize Travis CI's <a href="https://docs.travis-ci.com/user/cron-jobs/">cron functionality</a>. Every day, Travis will automatically trigger jobs that do nothing but build pump.io Docker images. These images are then pushed to Docker Hub. If nothing has changed, Docker Hub recognizes that the "new" images are actually identical with what's already there, and nothing happens. But if there <em>has</em> been a change, like a native dependency receiving a security update, then the image ID will change and Docker Hub will accept the updated image. This cronjob is enabled for the <code>5.1.x</code> branch and master (which as a side effect, means that alpha Docker images are published within 24 hours of a git push), and in the future it will be enabled on all branches that we actively support. Thus, Docker users can easily set up automation to ensure that they're running insecure images for, at most, 24 hours.</p>
<p>If you're interested in trying out the Docker images, we'd love to know how it goes. They should still be treated as experimental at the moment, and early feedback would be super useful. You can read more details in our <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/installation/about-docker-images.html">ReadTheDocs documentation</a>.</p>
<p>Note that there are still more changes that we'd like to make to the Docker images. These changes didn't make it into the 5.1.1 packaging since they felt too invasive for a patch release. Instead we plan to make them in the next release, which is planned to be semver-major. Which brings me neatly to the last topic...</p>
<h1>Sunsetting Node 4, 5, and 7 support</h1>
<p>We had a good run, but it's time to say goodbye: Node.js upstream has <a href="https://medium.com/the-node-js-collection/april-2018-release-updates-from-the-node-js-project-71687e1f7742">marked</a> Node 4.x as end-of-life, and in accordance with our <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Node.js-version-support">version policy</a>, we're doing the same. Since this is a semver-major change, we're also taking the opportunity to drop support for Node 5.x and Node 7.x. These changes have been made as of commit <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/commit/32ad78812ed767621418b8dd57f11ce86a01b49f">32ad78</a>, and soon we'll be ripping out old code used to support these versions, as well as upgrading dependencies that have recently started requiring newer Nodes.</p>
<p>Anyone still on these versions is encouraged to upgrade as soon as possible, as Node.js upstream is no longer providing security support for them. Administrators can use the <a href="https://github.com/nodesource/distributions">NodeSource</a> packages, or they can try out our new Docker images, which use a modern Node version internally.</p>
<p>Please reach out to the <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">community</a> if you need any help making the transition. And good luck!</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2018/05/pump.io-5.1.1-docker-images-and-node-4</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2018/05/pump.io-5.1.1-docker-images-and-node-4</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 20:06:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io 5.1 stable published to npm]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Last night I officially published pump.io 5.1 to npm as a stable release!</p>
<p>As I wrote in the beta announcement, this release contains a variety of improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/08/zero-downtime-restarts-have-landed">Zero-downtime restarts</a>, which allows administrators to seamlessly roll over to new configurations and codebases</li>
<li>The daemon now generates startup log warnings on bad configurations, including insecure <code>secret</code> values and internal parameters</li>
<li>An official <code>Dockerfile</code> is now included with the release</li>
<li>The logged-out mobile homepage's menu icon is no longer incorrectly styled as black</li>
<li>An authorization problem with SockJS connections has been fixed</li>
</ul>
<p>5.1 stable <em>does</em> include one change the beta didn't: a bump to the version of the <code>gm</code> npm package which we depend on. This bump was done as a precautionary measure, as previous versions of <code>gm</code> depended on a version of the <code>debug</code> module which was vulnerable to denial-of-service security bugs.</p>
<p>As a project, we addressed these bugs <a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/10/denial-of-service-security-fixes-now-available">back in October</a> when we issued security releases for all supported release branches, and at the time we confirmed that the vulnerable function wasn't used by <code>gm</code>. Today's <code>gm</code> bump does <em>not</em> constitute a security release; instead, we're just bumping the version as a precautionary measure in case we missed something in October's assessment of the situation.</p>
<p>Aside from the <code>gm</code> bump, there are (as usual) miscellaneous version bumps included in this release. We've also started tracking test suite coverage information as well as overhauled our <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/">documentation on ReadTheDocs</a>, moving most of the in-repository documentation there.</p>
<p>If you want even more details of this release, you can also check out <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#510---2018-01-05">the changelog</a>.</p>
<p>pump 5.1 is a drop-in replacement for 5.0. That means if you're using our recommended installation method and installing from npm, you can upgrade with <code>npm install -g pump.io@5.1</code>. If you have a source-based install, you should merge and/or switch to the <code>v5.1.0</code> tag. And as always, if you encounter any problems, please feel free to reach out to the <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">community</a> or <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/issues">file bugs you find</a>.</p>
<p>Finally, I would be remiss if I didn't point out that pump.io has a <strong>brand-new announcement mailing list</strong>! While the blog is great for announcing new releases, not everyone finds it convenient to check. Also, if we issue new betas in the middle of a release cycle, these aren't typically announced on the blog. Therefore in the future <em>all</em> new releases will be announced on the mailing list, not just initial betas. If you want to subscribe to the mailing list, you may do so <a href="https://lists.strugee.net/mailman/listinfo/pumpio-announce">here</a> - you'll get announcements of new features only, not e.g. feature announcements as seen on this blog. I hope people find this service useful!</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2018/01/pump.io-5.1-stable-published-to-npm</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2018/01/pump.io-5.1-stable-published-to-npm</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 04:09:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io 5.1 is in beta]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm really excited to announce that pump.io 5.1 is officially in beta!</p>
<p>This release makes a wide array of improvements. One of the features I'm most excited about is <a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/08/zero-downtime-restarts-have-landed">zero-downtime restarts</a>, which will allow administrators to gracefully roll over to new configurations and codebases with absolutely no user-visible impact! Aside from that, here's a list of highlights:</p>
<ul>
<li>The daemon now generates startup log warnings on bad configurations, including insecure <code>secret</code> values and internal parameters</li>
<li>An official <code>Dockerfile</code> is now included with the release</li>
<li>The logged-out mobile homepage's menu icon is no longer incorrectly styled as black</li>
<li>SockJS connections no longer fail due to authorization problems</li>
</ul>
<p>As usual, this release also includes some small updates to dependencies. Plus, we started tracking how much code our test suite covers! We've also significantly cleaned up the documentation and moved almost all of the in-repository documentation to ReadTheDocs, where it's a lot more organized and accessible. If you want more than just these highlights, you can check out <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#510-beta-0---2017-12-08">the changelog</a>.</p>
<p>Note that while the repository includes a <code>Dockerfile</code> now, we have not yet begun publishing on Docker Hub due to some security logistics that need to be figured out - when we do, it'll be announced in all the usual places (including this blog).</p>
<p>I'm so excited for people to try out this release. 5.1 beta 0 is a drop-in replacement for 5.0, so if you're on 5.0 and want to live (more) on the bleeding edge, you can upgrade with <code>npm install -g pump.io@5.1</code> if you have an npm-based install. If you have a source-based install, you should merge and/or switch to the <code>v5.1.0-beta.0</code> tag. And as always, if you encounter any problems you can reach out to the <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">community</a> or <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/issues">file bugs you find</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/12/pump.io-5.1-is-in-beta</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/12/pump.io-5.1-is-in-beta</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 20:24:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Denial-of-service security fixes now available]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Recently some denial-of-service vulnerabilities were discovered in various modules that we indirectly depend on. I've bumped Express and <code>send</code> to pull in patched versions, and I've updated our fork of <code>connect-auth</code> to require a patched version of Connect, too. The remaining vulnerabilities I've confirmed don't affect us.</p>
<p>Because of these version bumps, I've just put out security releases which all administrators are encouraged to upgrade to as soon as possible. A semver-major release (5.0.0) was released within the past 6 months so per our <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Security">security support policy</a> this means there are three new releases:</p>
<ol>
<li>pump.io 5.0.2 replaces 5.0.0 and is available now on npm</li>
<li>pump.io 4.1.3 replaces 4.1.2 and is available now on npm</li>
<li>pump.io 4.0.2 will replace 4.0.1 <strike>and is currently undergoing automated testing (it'll be on npm shortly)</strike> <strong>Update:</strong> pump.io 4.0.2 is now on npm</li>
</ol>
<p>As these are security releases we encourage admins to upgrade as soon as possible. If you're on 5.0.0 installed via npm - our recommended configuration - you can upgrade by issuing:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@5
</code></pre>
<p>If you're on 4.1.3, you can upgrade by issuing:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@4
</code></pre>
<p>And when 4.0.2 is out, if you're on 4.0.1 you can upgrade by issuing:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@4.0
</code></pre>
<p>Note though that 4.1.3 is a drop-in replacement for 4.0.2, so you should consider just upgrading to that instead. Or even better, <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/upgrades/4.x-to-5.x.html">upgrade to 5.x</a>!</p>
<p>If you don't have an npm-based install, you'll have to upgrade however you normally do. How to do this will depend on your particular setup.</p>
<p>As always, if you need help, you should get in touch with <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">the community</a>. I'd also like to specifically thank <a href="https://identi.ca/jxself">Jason Self</a>, who generously deployed a 24-hour private beta of these fixes on <a href="https://datamost.com/">Datamost</a>. One of the version bumps was ever-so-slightly risky, and being able to test things in production before rolling out patches for the entire network was invaluable. I wouldn't be as confident as I am in these releases without his help. So thanks, Jason - I really appreciate it!</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/10/denial-of-service-security-fixes-now-available</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/10/denial-of-service-security-fixes-now-available</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><category><![CDATA[security]]></category><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 17:40:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io 5.0 declared stable]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm super excited to announce that as of a couple days ago, pump.io 5.0 has now been declared stable and released!</p>
<p>This release cycle had an extra beta since I found a bug with the new display of shares. The fix ended up being trivial, though, and other than that there's been no changes from <a href="http://pump.io/blog/">the beta announcement</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Documentation has been expanded</li>
<li>Small improvements to the administrator experience have landed</li>
<li>The web UI has gotten, among other things, some user experience polishing as well as upgrades to more performant and better-licensed libraries</li>
<li>"Login with remote account" no longer crashes (although this one was backported in 4.1.1)</li>
<li>The <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/administration/upstream-systemd-unit.html">systemd service</a>  shipped with the package has significant security improvements</li>
<li>Lots of internal refactoring and simplification made possible by dropping Node 0.10/0.12 support</li>
</ul>
<p>As I said in the beta announcement, some of these changes - particularly the systemd changes and the fact that (<a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/07/pump.io-4.1-is-out">as previously announced</a>) Node 0.10 and 0.12 are no longer supported - will require administrator intervention. Be sure to read our <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/upgrades/4.x-to-5.x.html">upgrade guide</a> for details on how to deal with these.</p>
<p>pump.io 5.0 is the most stable and secure release yet, so as always, I'd encourage all administrators to upgrade as soon as possible. And if you get stuck, the <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">community</a> is always here to help.</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/09/pump.io-5.0-declared-stable</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/09/pump.io-5.0-declared-stable</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 01:22:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io 5.0 beta released]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm excited to announce that pump.io 5.0.0 is now officially in beta!</p>
<p>This is another big release and makes a wide variety of improvements. Here are some highlights from <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#500-beta-0---2017-08-07">the changelog</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>More complete documentation</li>
<li>Small improvements to the administrator experience</li>
<li>A better web UI, including some user experience polishing as well as an upgrade to more performant and better-licensed libraries</li>
<li>A fix for crashes related to "login with remote account" (although this one was backported in 4.1.1)</li>
<li>Significant security improvements in the <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/administration/upstream-systemd-unit.html">systemd service</a> shipped with the package</li>
<li>Lots of internal refactoring and simplification made possible by dropping Node 0.10/0.12 support</li>
</ul>
<p>Many of these changes - particularly the systemd changes and the fact that (<a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/07/pump.io-4.1-is-out">as previously announced</a>) Node 0.10 and 0.12 are no longer supported - will require administrator intervention. Be sure to read our <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/upgrades/4.x-to-5.x.html">upgrade guide</a> for details on how to deal with these changes.</p>
<p>All of these features add up to make pump.io 5.0 beta the most stable and secure release yet. As always, it will go through our beta period for about a month before being released as a fully stable version. If you try it out, the <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">community</a> would love to hear about it - and be sure to <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/issues">report any bugs</a> you encounter!</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/08/pump.io-5.0-beta-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/08/pump.io-5.0-beta-released</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 14:51:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io 4.1 is out]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>pump.io 4.1 is out!</p>
<p>As usual, nothing much has changed since <a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/06/out-now-pump.io-4.1-beta">the beta release</a>. This release includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Minor web UI improvements</li>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/Subresource_Integrity">Subresource Integrity</a> in the web UI</li>
<li>A switch to a pure-JavaScript bcrypt, which should improve installs on non x86 platforms and Docker</li>
<li>Some other <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#410-beta-0---2017-06-15">minor improvements and fixes</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Remember that <a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/06/out-now-pump.io-4.1-beta">with this release</a>, Node 0.10 and Node 0.12 support is officially obsolete. This change paves the way for a lot of really important improvements, and in fact, we've already introduced a lot of changes that reduce technical debt. Note that since the beta announcement, Debian Stretch has been released, which ships Node 4 in <code>main</code>. You can read more about our Node.js support policy <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Node.js-version-support">on our wiki</a>.</p>
<p>Enjoy the new release, and remember to <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/issues">report any bugs</a>!</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/07/pump.io-4.1-is-out</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/07/pump.io-4.1-is-out</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 18:57:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Out now: pump.io 4.1 beta]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps some of you were wondering where pump.io's 4.1 release was, since our <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Release-cycle">release schedule</a> says it should've been released at the beginning of this month?</p>
<p>Well, wonder no longer. This release was unfortunately delayed because of some big stuff in my personal life that got in the way of free software stuff (sorry!), but as of yesteray, pump.io 4.1 is officially in beta! Huzzah!</p>
<p>This was a relatively minor release, primarily improving some aspects of the web UI. Notably, the pump.io 4.1 beta includes support for <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/Subresource_Integrity">Subresource Integrity</a>, a web standard which will improve security for users on nodes with <code>"noCDN": false</code> in their pump.io configurations. A more complete list of changes is available in the <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#410-beta-0---2017-06-15">change log</a>.</p>
<p>As always, we advise caution when upgrading to beta releases. Please <a href="http://pump.io/blog/">report</a> any problems or bugs you encounter.</p>
<p>pump.io 4.1 beta is a drop-in replacement for pump.io 4.0.</p>
<h1>First time contributors</h1>
<p>I would like to specially thank the following people, who contributed to the pump.io project for the first time during this release cycle:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/vxcamiloxv">Camilo QS</a>, who contributed a number of improvements to the web UI</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/bio-boris">@bio-boris</a>, who implemented <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/Subresource_Integrity">Subresource Integrity</a> for the web UI</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/RyanRiddle">Ryan Riddle</a>, who made the web UI proactively warn if the user was trying to sign up with a blacklisted/reserved username (like <code>api</code> or <code>robots.txt</code>)</li>
</ul>
<h1>Node.js 0.10 and 0.12 support ending</h1>
<p>Finally, the stable release pump.io 4.1 will mark the end of pump.io's support for Node.js 0.10 and 0.12. These versions of Node are extremely old and are preventing us from making serious improvements to the codebase - you can see a list of these in <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/issues/1234">issue #1234</a>. Note that in particular we cannot simultaneously support Node 7 and Node 0.10 due to our browser unit testing library, Zombie.</p>
<p>With the exception of Red Hat Enterprise Linux and CentOS, there are <a href="https://nodecompat.com/">no major Linux distributions</a> not shipping Node 4+ in some form. Most of them ship it out-of-the-box; the only one that does not is Debian. For our admins on Debian, Node 4 is available in <code>jessie-backports</code> and will become the officially supported version with the release of Debian Stretch (which is imminent). Plus, for all of these platforms, NodeSource offers <a href="https://github.com/nodesource/distributions">binary packages</a> for all major Node versions that can be installed and managed through the system package manager. We'll also soon be making a Docker image available, which will allow people to run pump.io on any Docker-capable host, regardless of what Node version is shipped with their distribution.</p>
<p>You can read more about our Node.js version support policy <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Node.js-version-support-policy">on our wiki</a>.</p>
<p>Here's to another pump.io beta!</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/06/out-now-pump.io-4.1-beta</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/06/out-now-pump.io-4.1-beta</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 02:46:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io XSS security releases available]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Well, apparently I forgot to make a blog post announcing that pump.io 4.0.0 stable is out. Surprise! Besides the version number it's the same as <a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/04/pump.io-4.0-in-beta">4.0 beta 5</a> anyway.</p>
<p>What is not the same as 4.0 beta 5, however, is the security releases I've just published. A semver-major release went out within the past 6 months, so per our <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Security">security support policy</a>, we've released security patches for the past three stable releases:</p>
<ol>
<li>pump.io 4.0.0 has been updated to pump.io 4.0.1</li>
<li>pump.io 3.0.2 has been updated to pump.io 3.0.3</li>
<li>pump.io 2.1.1 has been updated to pump.io 2.1.2</li>
</ol>
<p>So what exactly required these releases? Well, the library we use to prevent cross-site scripting, <a href="https://github.com/cure53/DOMPurify">DOMPurify</a>, released some security patches recently. While we could conceivably just tell pump.io users to rerun <code>npm install -g</code> to get the updated library, it seemed safer to issue patch releases that bumped the minimum version for DOMPurify and have people upgrade to those. This gives a 100% guarantee that pump.io users will be protected with the absolute latest DOMPurify version.</p>
<p>As with any security release, we encourage admins to upgrade ASAP. If you've already installed the 4.0 release via npm, that's great! That's our recommended configuration, and you'll be able to upgrade by issuing:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@4
</code></pre>
<p>If you're still on the 3.x release series, you really should <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/upgrades/3.x-to-4.x.html">upgrade to 4.x</a>, which contains significant work impacting security which was too big to go into a patch release (specifically, the upgrade to Express 4.x). But in the meantime, you can fix your XSS problems by running:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@3
</code></pre>
<p>And something similar if you're on 2.1.x:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@2
</code></pre>
<p>Though in this case it's even more urgent that you <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/upgrades/3.x-to-4.x.html">upgrade to 4.x</a>.</p>
<p>Note that the above comands also assume you have an npm-based install, which we strongly recommend. If you have a source-based install, you will need to upgrade however you usually do - this will depend on how exactly you have pump.io set up.</p>
<p>As always, if you need help, get in touch with <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">the community</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/05/pump.io-xss-security-releases-available</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/05/pump.io-xss-security-releases-available</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><category><![CDATA[security]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 01:59:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io 4.0 in beta]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>pump.io 4.0.0 is officially in beta! Whooo!</p>
<h1>Highlights</h1>
<p>This is a positively <em>huge</em> release, and I'm so excited to share it with the community. Some highlights:</p>
<ul>
<li>Express 4.x - I wrote about the significance of this change <a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/03/express-4.x-in-pump.io-core">here</a>, but suffice to say that this significantly improves security, performance, and future maintainability</li>
<li>Performance and correctness improvements to the web UI's JavaScript</li>
<li>Better administrative experience, including the ability to specify configuration via environment variables</li>
<li>Better interoperability with the <a href="https://indieweb.org">IndieWeb</a></li>
</ul>
<h1>Upgrading</h1>
<p>The upgrade to Express 4.x and the improvements to configuration loading have the potential to break <em>some</em> existing pump.io installations, although 95% of installs should be completely unaffected. If you want to help test this beta, please set aside extra time as necessary to perform this upgrade - full documentation can be found on <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/upgrades/3.x-to-4.x.html">ReadTheDocs</a>.</p>
<p>As always, this release will follow our normal <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Release-cycle">release cycle</a>, which means that the stable 4.0.0 release will go out in about a month.</p>
<h1>Test days</h1>
<p>Due to the complexity of this upgrade, we've decided to have some test days during the beta where we upgrade prominent nodes for a day, then downgrade them again. This will help expose problems earlier and make the upgrade smoother for everyone. So far Jason Self, who runs <a href="https://datamost.com/">Datamost</a>, has volunteered for this - if you're interested in joining him, please <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">get in touch</a>!</p>
<p>Happy hacking!</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/04/pump.io-4.0-in-beta</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/04/pump.io-4.0-in-beta</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 17:03:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pump.io 2.0.4 is available]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Greetings!</p>
<p>After a beta period of just over a week, pump.io 2.0.4 is now available on npm and GitHub. Whoohoo!</p>
<p>(This was originally going to be 2.0.0, but we had to do a couple patch releases due to some outdated documentation and several critical bugs. 2.0.4 is mostly the same thing as 2.0.0.)</p>
<h2>Changes</h2>
<p>Note that this release includes security improvements - namely, a newer Express version and a better TLS configuration - and therefore <strong>admins are encouraged to upgrade ASAP</strong>.</p>
<p>For the full list of changes, see <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#201---2016-11-10">the change log</a>.</p>
<h3>Breaking changes</h3>
<p>(As I said in <a href="http://pump.io/blog/">the beta announcement</a>:)</p>
<p>Pump.io 2.0.4 is a drop-in replacement for 1.0.0 <strong>unless</strong> you have any plugins configured or you modify the templates.</p>
<p>Plugins are likely to be affected by the upgrade to Express 3.x. The easiest way to migrate is probably to just run pump.io, test out the relevant parts of the app, and see where your plugin crashes. You might also want to look at the <a href="https://github.com/expressjs/express/blob/master/History.md#300--2012-10-23">Express 3 change log</a>.</p>
<p>If you modified the templates, you'll be affected by the templates' rewrite from utml into Jade. Migration should be relatively painless but has to be done manually. Your best bet will be to save a copy of the diff you created, undo your changes, upgrade, then use the diff you saved to reintroduce your changes. You'll have to run <code>npm run build</code> after making changes to Jade files.</p>
<h3>Non-breaking changes</h3>
<p>This release is actually relatively minor in terms of non-breaking changes; however, we <em>do</em> have some nice new improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li>A pump(1) manpage is now included</li>
<li>Any internal web UI link with a <code>data-bypass</code> attribute is now ignored by the routing logic (useful for e.g. custom pages added by the admin)</li>
<li>YouTube links in posts are now shown as  embeds by the web UI (<a href="https://github.com/expressjs/express/blob/master/History.md#300--2012-10-23">#1158</a>)</li>
<li>TLS connections now use Mozilla's "intermediate" cipher suite and forces server cipher suite preferences (<a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/issues/1061">#1061</a>)</li>
<li>Various minor fixes and improvements</li>
</ul>
<h2>Upgrading</h2>
<p>Upgrading is dead-simple. If you used our recommended install method, and installed from npm, you can upgrade with:</p>
<pre><code>sudo npm install -g pump.io@2
</code></pre>
<p>If you installed from source, you can upgrade with:</p>
<pre><code>git fetch
# If you modified templates, save the diff at this step
git checkout .
git checkout v2.0.4
npm install
# Restore your template changes
npm run lint:jade # Optional but recommended if you changed templates
npm run build
</code></pre>
<p>Both of these methods will work whether you're running 0.3.0, 1.0.0, or 2.0.0 beta. Make sure to restart pump.io after performing the upgrade.</p>
<h2>Getting help</h2>
<p>If you have any issues with the upgrade, get in touch with <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">the community</a>. You can also email me at <a href="mailto:alex@strugee.net">alex@strugee.net</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2016/11/pump.io-2.0.1-is-available</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2016/11/pump.io-2.0.1-is-available</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 23:49:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pump.io 2.0.0 beta is here]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Greetings!</p>
<p>As pump.io is gearing up for our 2.0.0 release, I just published a beta to npm. We'd love it if any interested admins could upgrade their nodes and report any bugs you may run in to. (All bug reports are helpful, but just so we're clear, we're likely to only fix regressions from 1.0.0.)</p>
<h2>Changes</h2>
<p>Pump.io 2.0.0 beta is a drop-in replacement for 1.0.0 <strong>unless</strong> you have any plugins configured or you modify the templates.</p>
<p>Plugins are likely to be affected by the upgrade to Express 3.x. The easiest way to migrate is probably to just run pump.io, test out the relevant parts of the app, and see where your plugin crashes. You might also want to look at the <a href="https://github.com/expressjs/express/blob/master/History.md#300--2012-10-23">Express 3 change log</a>.</p>
<p>If you modified the templates, you'll be affected by the templates' rewrite from utml into Jade. Migration should be relatively painless but has to be done manually. Your best bet will be to save a copy of the diff you created, undo your changes, upgrade, then use the diff you saved to reintroduce your changes. You'll have to run <code>npm run build</code> after making changes to Jade files.</p>
<p>For the list of non-breaking changes, see <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#200-beta-1---2016-11-02">the change log</a>.</p>
<h2>Upgrading</h2>
<p>Upgrading is very easy. If you used our recommended install method, and installed from npm, you can upgrade to the beta with:</p>
<pre><code>sudo npm install -g pump.io@beta
</code></pre>
<p>If you installed from source, you can upgrade with:</p>
<pre><code>git fetch
# If you modified templates, save the diff at this step
git checkout .
git checkout v2.0.0-beta.1
npm install
# Restore your template changes
npm run lint:jade # Optional but recommended if you changed templates
npm run build
</code></pre>
<p>Make sure to restart pump.io after performing the upgrade.</p>
<h2>Getting help</h2>
<p>If you have any issues upgrading to or running the beta, please don't hesitate to get in touch with <a href="https://github.com/e14n/pump.io/wiki/Community">the community</a>. You can also email me at <a href="mailto:alex@strugee.net">alex@strugee.net</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2016/11/pump.io-2.0.0-beta-is-here</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2016/11/pump.io-2.0.0-beta-is-here</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 20:05:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pump.io 1.0.0 is now available!]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/e14n/pump.io/releases/tag/v1.0.0">Pump.io 1.0.0</a> is officially available! Whoooo!</p>
<p>I just wanted to write up an announcement real quick to celebrate. Here's a sample what's gone into this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Node 4.x support</li>
<li>Lots of security improvements including a better cross-site scripting scrubber and security-related headers that help protect the web UI (most notably, the web UI now declares a Content Security Policy)</li>
<li>Minor improvements to the API to make it (slightly) smarter</li>
<li><a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/librejs/">LibreJS</a> support</li>
<li>Numerous dependency upgrades, most notably Connect</li>
<li>And of course, tons of minor bugfixes and improvements</li>
</ul>
<p>For more details, see the brand-new <a href="https://github.com/e14n/pump.io/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#100---2016-08-26">change log</a>.</p>
<p>And of course since we're now past 0.x.x releases, we're now officially making a commitment to the community to make only API-compatible changes going forward (or at least, until 2.0.0!).</p>
<p>As this release <em>does</em> improve security and fixes a lot of bugs, node administrators are encouraged to upgrade as soon as possible. If you have a global, npm-based install, you can upgrade with:</p>
<pre><code>sudo npm install -g pump.io
</code></pre>
<p>And with a source-based install:</p>
<pre><code>git pull
git checkout v1.0.0
npm install --production
</code></pre>
<p>If you're upgrading from 0.3.0, everything should Just Work(tm). Don't forget to restart your daemon!</p>
<p>One final note - the rumors are true. While we're not doing so <em>yet</em>, we are, in fact, planning to deprecate running under Node.js 0.10 and 0.12 very soon. Also, if you upgrade to Node.js 4.x early, the new, better XSS scrubber will be enabled - <em>however</em>, be aware that pump.io is far less tested under Node.js 4.x and you are likely to run into more bugs than you would under 0.10 or 0.12. This is an unfortunate situation, but sadly there's really nothing to be done about it. :(</p>
<p>Special thanks to Menno Vossen, Laura Arjona, Evan Prodromou, Jan Kusanagi and all the other volunteers who did so many different things to make this release happen. It truly wouldn't have happened without you.</p>
<p>Enjoy the release!</p>
<p>With &lt;3,</p>
<p>AJ</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2016/08/pump.io-1.0.0-is-now-available</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2016/08/pump.io-1.0.0-is-now-available</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><category><![CDATA[code]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 23:37:54 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>