<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[pump.io blog - September - 2017]]></title><description><![CDATA[pump.io blog - September - 2017]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/09</link><generator>stratic-indexes-to-rss</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 01:52:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/09/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright><![CDATA[© Copyright 2016-2017 pump.io contributors.]]></copyright><webMaster><![CDATA[AJ Jordan <alex@strugee.net>]]></webMaster><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io 5.0 declared stable]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm super excited to announce that as of a couple days ago, pump.io 5.0 has now been declared stable and released!</p>
<p>This release cycle had an extra beta since I found a bug with the new display of shares. The fix ended up being trivial, though, and other than that there's been no changes from <a href="http://pump.io/blog/">the beta announcement</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Documentation has been expanded</li>
<li>Small improvements to the administrator experience have landed</li>
<li>The web UI has gotten, among other things, some user experience polishing as well as upgrades to more performant and better-licensed libraries</li>
<li>"Login with remote account" no longer crashes (although this one was backported in 4.1.1)</li>
<li>The <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/administration/upstream-systemd-unit.html">systemd service</a>  shipped with the package has significant security improvements</li>
<li>Lots of internal refactoring and simplification made possible by dropping Node 0.10/0.12 support</li>
</ul>
<p>As I said in the beta announcement, some of these changes - particularly the systemd changes and the fact that (<a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/07/pump.io-4.1-is-out">as previously announced</a>) Node 0.10 and 0.12 are no longer supported - will require administrator intervention. Be sure to read our <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/upgrades/4.x-to-5.x.html">upgrade guide</a> for details on how to deal with these.</p>
<p>pump.io 5.0 is the most stable and secure release yet, so as always, I'd encourage all administrators to upgrade as soon as possible. And if you get stuck, the <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">community</a> is always here to help.</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/09/pump.io-5.0-declared-stable</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/09/pump.io-5.0-declared-stable</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 01:22:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>