<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[pump.io blog - 2019]]></title><description><![CDATA[pump.io blog - 2019]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2019</link><generator>stratic-indexes-to-rss</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 07:16:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://pump.io/blog/2019/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright><![CDATA[© Copyright 2016-2017 pump.io contributors.]]></copyright><webMaster><![CDATA[AJ Jordan <alex@strugee.net>]]></webMaster><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io DOMPurify security fixes available]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Recently the cross-site-scripting sanitization library that pump.io uses, <a href="https://github.com/cure53/DOMPurify">DOMPurify</a>, published several security advisories for mXSS vulnerabilities affecting browsers based on the Blink rendering engine - you can find the latest one, for example, <a href="https://lists.ruhr-uni-bochum.de/pipermail/dompurify-security/2019-October/000012.html">here</a>. As we've done in the past, the pump.io project is publishing security releases to ensure that everyone is using the latest version of DOMPurify. Per our <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Security">security support policy</a>, we are providing patches for the current stable release and the previous stable release:</p>
<ol>
<li>pump.io 5.1.2 has been updated to pump.io 5.1.3</li>
<li>pump.io 5.0.2 has been updated to pump.io 5.0.3</li>
</ol>
<p>As these are security releases we encourage administrators to upgrade as soon as possible. Both 5.1.3 and 5.0.3 are drop-in replacements for their predecessors. If you have pump.io 5.1 installed via npm - our recommended configuration - you can upgrade with:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@5
</code></pre>
<p>If you're on pump.io 5.0, we recommend that you also run the above command to upgrade to 5.1 - it's a drop-in replacement for 5.0. However, if you want to stick with 5.0 for the time being, you can install a patched version with:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@5.0
</code></pre>
<p>Note that if you have a source-based install, the above commands won't work and you will need to upgrade however you usually do - this will depend on how exactly you have pump.io set up.</p>
<p>If you need help, or if you have questions about these security releases, get in touch with <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">the community</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2019/10/pump.io-dompurify-security-fixes-available</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2019/10/pump.io-dompurify-security-fixes-available</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><category><![CDATA[security]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 18:28:01 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>