<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[pump.io blog - April - 2017]]></title><description><![CDATA[pump.io blog - April - 2017]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/04</link><generator>stratic-indexes-to-rss</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 04:15:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/04/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright><![CDATA[© Copyright 2016-2017 pump.io contributors.]]></copyright><webMaster><![CDATA[AJ Jordan <alex@strugee.net>]]></webMaster><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io 4.0 in beta]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>pump.io 4.0.0 is officially in beta! Whooo!</p>
<h1>Highlights</h1>
<p>This is a positively <em>huge</em> release, and I'm so excited to share it with the community. Some highlights:</p>
<ul>
<li>Express 4.x - I wrote about the significance of this change <a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/03/express-4.x-in-pump.io-core">here</a>, but suffice to say that this significantly improves security, performance, and future maintainability</li>
<li>Performance and correctness improvements to the web UI's JavaScript</li>
<li>Better administrative experience, including the ability to specify configuration via environment variables</li>
<li>Better interoperability with the <a href="https://indieweb.org">IndieWeb</a></li>
</ul>
<h1>Upgrading</h1>
<p>The upgrade to Express 4.x and the improvements to configuration loading have the potential to break <em>some</em> existing pump.io installations, although 95% of installs should be completely unaffected. If you want to help test this beta, please set aside extra time as necessary to perform this upgrade - full documentation can be found on <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/upgrades/3.x-to-4.x.html">ReadTheDocs</a>.</p>
<p>As always, this release will follow our normal <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Release-cycle">release cycle</a>, which means that the stable 4.0.0 release will go out in about a month.</p>
<h1>Test days</h1>
<p>Due to the complexity of this upgrade, we've decided to have some test days during the beta where we upgrade prominent nodes for a day, then downgrade them again. This will help expose problems earlier and make the upgrade smoother for everyone. So far Jason Self, who runs <a href="https://datamost.com/">Datamost</a>, has volunteered for this - if you're interested in joining him, please <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">get in touch</a>!</p>
<p>Happy hacking!</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/04/pump.io-4.0-in-beta</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/04/pump.io-4.0-in-beta</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 17:03:10 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>