<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[pump.io blog - 'security' category]]></title><description><![CDATA[pump.io blog - 'security' category]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/category/security</link><generator>stratic-indexes-to-rss</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 23:50:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://pump.io/blog/category/security/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright><![CDATA[© Copyright 2016-2017 pump.io contributors.]]></copyright><webMaster><![CDATA[AJ Jordan <alex@strugee.net>]]></webMaster><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io DOMPurify security fixes available]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Recently the cross-site-scripting sanitization library that pump.io uses, <a href="https://github.com/cure53/DOMPurify">DOMPurify</a>, published several security advisories for mXSS vulnerabilities affecting browsers based on the Blink rendering engine - you can find the latest one, for example, <a href="https://lists.ruhr-uni-bochum.de/pipermail/dompurify-security/2019-October/000012.html">here</a>. As we've done in the past, the pump.io project is publishing security releases to ensure that everyone is using the latest version of DOMPurify. Per our <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Security">security support policy</a>, we are providing patches for the current stable release and the previous stable release:</p>
<ol>
<li>pump.io 5.1.2 has been updated to pump.io 5.1.3</li>
<li>pump.io 5.0.2 has been updated to pump.io 5.0.3</li>
</ol>
<p>As these are security releases we encourage administrators to upgrade as soon as possible. Both 5.1.3 and 5.0.3 are drop-in replacements for their predecessors. If you have pump.io 5.1 installed via npm - our recommended configuration - you can upgrade with:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@5
</code></pre>
<p>If you're on pump.io 5.0, we recommend that you also run the above command to upgrade to 5.1 - it's a drop-in replacement for 5.0. However, if you want to stick with 5.0 for the time being, you can install a patched version with:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@5.0
</code></pre>
<p>Note that if you have a source-based install, the above commands won't work and you will need to upgrade however you usually do - this will depend on how exactly you have pump.io set up.</p>
<p>If you need help, or if you have questions about these security releases, get in touch with <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">the community</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2019/10/pump.io-dompurify-security-fixes-available</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2019/10/pump.io-dompurify-security-fixes-available</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><category><![CDATA[security]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 18:28:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Denial-of-service security fixes now available]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Recently some denial-of-service vulnerabilities were discovered in various modules that we indirectly depend on. I've bumped Express and <code>send</code> to pull in patched versions, and I've updated our fork of <code>connect-auth</code> to require a patched version of Connect, too. The remaining vulnerabilities I've confirmed don't affect us.</p>
<p>Because of these version bumps, I've just put out security releases which all administrators are encouraged to upgrade to as soon as possible. A semver-major release (5.0.0) was released within the past 6 months so per our <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Security">security support policy</a> this means there are three new releases:</p>
<ol>
<li>pump.io 5.0.2 replaces 5.0.0 and is available now on npm</li>
<li>pump.io 4.1.3 replaces 4.1.2 and is available now on npm</li>
<li>pump.io 4.0.2 will replace 4.0.1 <strike>and is currently undergoing automated testing (it'll be on npm shortly)</strike> <strong>Update:</strong> pump.io 4.0.2 is now on npm</li>
</ol>
<p>As these are security releases we encourage admins to upgrade as soon as possible. If you're on 5.0.0 installed via npm - our recommended configuration - you can upgrade by issuing:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@5
</code></pre>
<p>If you're on 4.1.3, you can upgrade by issuing:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@4
</code></pre>
<p>And when 4.0.2 is out, if you're on 4.0.1 you can upgrade by issuing:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@4.0
</code></pre>
<p>Note though that 4.1.3 is a drop-in replacement for 4.0.2, so you should consider just upgrading to that instead. Or even better, <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/upgrades/4.x-to-5.x.html">upgrade to 5.x</a>!</p>
<p>If you don't have an npm-based install, you'll have to upgrade however you normally do. How to do this will depend on your particular setup.</p>
<p>As always, if you need help, you should get in touch with <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">the community</a>. I'd also like to specifically thank <a href="https://identi.ca/jxself">Jason Self</a>, who generously deployed a 24-hour private beta of these fixes on <a href="https://datamost.com/">Datamost</a>. One of the version bumps was ever-so-slightly risky, and being able to test things in production before rolling out patches for the entire network was invaluable. I wouldn't be as confident as I am in these releases without his help. So thanks, Jason - I really appreciate it!</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/10/denial-of-service-security-fixes-now-available</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/10/denial-of-service-security-fixes-now-available</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><category><![CDATA[security]]></category><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 17:40:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[pump.io XSS security releases available]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Well, apparently I forgot to make a blog post announcing that pump.io 4.0.0 stable is out. Surprise! Besides the version number it's the same as <a href="http://pump.io/blog/2017/04/pump.io-4.0-in-beta">4.0 beta 5</a> anyway.</p>
<p>What is not the same as 4.0 beta 5, however, is the security releases I've just published. A semver-major release went out within the past 6 months, so per our <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Security">security support policy</a>, we've released security patches for the past three stable releases:</p>
<ol>
<li>pump.io 4.0.0 has been updated to pump.io 4.0.1</li>
<li>pump.io 3.0.2 has been updated to pump.io 3.0.3</li>
<li>pump.io 2.1.1 has been updated to pump.io 2.1.2</li>
</ol>
<p>So what exactly required these releases? Well, the library we use to prevent cross-site scripting, <a href="https://github.com/cure53/DOMPurify">DOMPurify</a>, released some security patches recently. While we could conceivably just tell pump.io users to rerun <code>npm install -g</code> to get the updated library, it seemed safer to issue patch releases that bumped the minimum version for DOMPurify and have people upgrade to those. This gives a 100% guarantee that pump.io users will be protected with the absolute latest DOMPurify version.</p>
<p>As with any security release, we encourage admins to upgrade ASAP. If you've already installed the 4.0 release via npm, that's great! That's our recommended configuration, and you'll be able to upgrade by issuing:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@4
</code></pre>
<p>If you're still on the 3.x release series, you really should <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/upgrades/3.x-to-4.x.html">upgrade to 4.x</a>, which contains significant work impacting security which was too big to go into a patch release (specifically, the upgrade to Express 4.x). But in the meantime, you can fix your XSS problems by running:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@3
</code></pre>
<p>And something similar if you're on 2.1.x:</p>
<pre><code>$ npm install -g pump.io@2
</code></pre>
<p>Though in this case it's even more urgent that you <a href="https://pumpio.readthedocs.io/en/latest/upgrades/3.x-to-4.x.html">upgrade to 4.x</a>.</p>
<p>Note that the above comands also assume you have an npm-based install, which we strongly recommend. If you have a source-based install, you will need to upgrade however you usually do - this will depend on how exactly you have pump.io set up.</p>
<p>As always, if you need help, get in touch with <a href="https://github.com/pump-io/pump.io/wiki/Community">the community</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>http://pump.io/blog/2017/05/pump.io-xss-security-releases-available</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://pump.io/blog/2017/05/pump.io-xss-security-releases-available</guid><category><![CDATA[releases]]></category><category><![CDATA[security]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 01:59:52 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>